In the first episode we talked about the basics
of what is going on in Brazil now: the honest
President - which supports actions against
corruption - is being casted out by the corrupt
politicians themselves, united.
How can such injustice happen?
We briefly mentioned the role of the mainstream
media on supporting a false perspective and
pushing it into a considerable slice of the
people.
By completely ignoring the bigger and serious
issues, while focusing and targeting heavily
on minor issues, the mainstream media pretends
that the true reasons for the impeachment
do not exist or are not important.
TRIPPING A COUNTRY UP
Dilma's impeachment is a big tragedy of huge
proportions. It is very important to be aware
of what is really at stake.
It is not only a coup in a person. It is not
only a coup in the Workers Party. It is even
more than a coup in the whole left wing. It
is not only a coup in the democracy. It is
a coup in Brazil.
And it is more than a coup in Brazil. It is
a coup in BRICS itself - the promising union
between Brazil, Russia, India, China and South
Africa. It is also a coup in all popular governments
in South America.
It is the meltdown of a nation's bright future.
Let's understand this better.
1. FIGHT AGAINST CORRUPTION
Dilma's support to the undertaking of investigations
against corruption is not mere discourse or
hypocrisy. It translates into actions and
numbers.
The operations and prisons related to corruption
are at historical heights. Several laws have
been created to properly detect and punish
illicit usage of public money. The Police is
not blocked or censored by the government
in the accomplishment of their
investigative tasks.
With this positioning and a strong hold on
making justice, Dilma has attracted the bad
will of a giant and powerful country-wide
network of illicit fortune making.
Corruption in Brazil is a real and big issue.
Truly standing against it is a courageous
act by itself.
Nevertheless, 100% of all citizens and politicians
agree on this point. Everybody speaks
"against corruption", including those who practice
it.
It is easy for me and for you to be against
corruption. Dilma suffers the consequences
of being President and really being against
corruption. Not only in words, but also in
thoughts and actions.
2. POLITICAL REFORM
In 2013, we had several manifestations in
Brazil, when a considerable number of people
went to streets to protest for change.
Political Reform was Dilma's answer to the
clamour coming from the streets.
The meaning of the message was: with the current
political system, chances for meaningful and
significant transformation are very restricted.
The proposed political reform represents a
series of changes on how the representatives
of the people are chosen, as well as how the
policies to be implemented are elaborated
and decided.
The core idea is to make public policies more
influenced by the public. Increase popular
participation in decisions. A movement towards
opening and participation. Towards transparency
and collaboration.
At that time, the role of the mainstream media
was either ignore or discredit the political
reform as suggested by Dilma, focusing on
minor aspects of it. In social networks, it
has been accused as a periculous communist
attack.
In September 2014, around 500 organizations
in the whole country promoted a plebiscite
to acknowledge people's support for a political reform
in Brazil. From a total of 7,754,436 votes,
97% declared to be favourable for a political
reform. Around 7.5 million voted "yes".
This is a very expressive achievement. But
silence is one of the mainstream media weapons.
Just like effectively acting against corruption,
in the same manner, seriously supporting the
idea of giving more power to the people through
a political reform is a solid path to attract
a handful of powerful enemies.
It should be easy to understand that those
who reap benefits from the
current corrupt political system do not want true changes on it.
3. MEDIA DEMOCRATIZATION
In the Brazilian Federal Constitution, article
220, 5th paragraph, it is explicitly expressed:
privately owned communication channels in
the country cannot be object of monopoly or
oligopoly.
To bring this single statement into reality
in Brazil would imply in dramatical changes
in the country's communications.
But this is only the tip of the iceberg: articles
220, 221, 222 and 223 paint a picture where
the media should translate the plurality of
voices that this rich country has.
Unfortunately, what we really have now here
is a powerful monolithic conglomerate which
tends to transform any dissonant voice into
ridicule - even if this voice is from the
Pope itself.
Raising the flag of bringing democracy to
communications resulted in unprecedent joint
of forces by the mainstream media against
Dilma's government.
Furthermore, the mainstream media depicts
the democratization initiative as censorship.
It is fairly the opposite: the democratization
aims to give voice to the unheard.
4. OIL AND EDUCATION
Each one of these can be seen as enough reason
for a government overthrow:
- true action against corruption,
- political reform support,
- media democratization
There is also another cause of concern for
the plutocracy who is driving the current
coup in Brazil. In one word: Education.
Ignorance is their strongest support.
Awareness is their true enemy.
Dilma's motto for her second mandate is: "Brazil,
Homeland of Education"
It is well-known in Brazil that due to Workers
Party governments, the country ended up removed
from the Hunger Map (which is a report made
by the United Nations).
After the successful accomplishment of this
basic first step - feeding the estomach - a
new goal was set: to feed people with knowledge
and culture.
This is a very expensive enterprise.
And this is where the oil factor comes in.
You may have heard about "pre-salt". The “pre-salt”
is an area of oil deposits found in deep saline
rock layer, which forms one of the various
rock layers in the seabed.
Ex-President Lula considered its discovery
in Brazil a God's blessing. The source of
money for the expensive enterprise of Education
in a continental-sized nation.
The value of pre-salt petroleum found in Brazilian
coast is estimated to be trillions of dollars.
Those interested in impeachment can easily
buy lots of Brazilian Congressmen with a tiny
fraction of this amount.
The intention of cheap selling this national
treasure for overseas companies has been explicitily
expressed. This intention is clearly stated
by Brazilian politicians in e-mail communications.
A few messages have been leaked in the internet
and, as usual, ignored by the mainstream media.
Brazil's strongest public company, the oil
giant Petrobrás, suffers a massive campaign
to burden its reputation. The goal is to transfer
it to private hands for the cheapest price
possible.
Again, the mainstream media plays a central
role. Citizens should be defending their treasure,
but they end up joining the media choir. They
promote the cheap sell as if the company had
been already stolen by the Workers Party.
While the fooled people is proud of "standing
against corruption", they are literally and
mercilessly killing the golden goose.
It is a shame that those elected and paid
by the people and for the people are making
themselves the destroyers of the education
and the resources of the own country.
5. BRICS
The single-handled and unchallenged financial
power behind the banks is geared towards one
thing: profit. This has been the sacred principle,
above all others.
When the creation of BRICS bank was announced,
it has been received as great news by many.
It has been perceived as if we would finally
begin to have some balance, by having a new
significant financial power geared towards
development.
BRICS - Brazil, Russia, India, China and South
Africa.
The national Brazilian mainstream media has
not given more than minimal attention to it.
Sincerely speaking, in Brazil, if you do not
have other reliable sources of information,
you are left in the dark. Even though you
consume news, you are left uninformed.
A coup in Brazil is also a coup in BRICS - weakening
this powerful coalition which has potential
to be effectively a global game changer.
THE SACRIFICE OF A BRIGHT FUTURE
In 2008, a global economical crisis was hitting
the world, but Brazil under the Workers Party
government didn't suffer a recession.
Similarly, in 2015, despite the catastrophic
tone of the media, Brazil was again going
through a severe global crisis with a reduced
impact and a positive perspective.
The government has not denied the existence
of a crisis and the necessity of adjustments,
which were done in 2015 and impacted negatively
the economy.
The perspective is to overcome it and start
growing again.
While the media focus exclusively in the crisis,
there are very positive and concrete aspects
of the current scenario: No hunger anymore.
Social inclusion. Steady increase of minimum
wage. World Cup. Olympics. Several new Federal
Universities. Big buildings - such as San
Francisco river transposition, Belo Monte
dam, railroads. And a bright Educational plan.
This and much much more is what is being thrown
away. We shall have an episode only to list
the good things going on, which are absolutely
"forgotten" by mainstream media.
It is also true that there is an economical
crisis going on right now. Despite all the
real issues the country still have to address,
none justify an impeachment.
Instead of help to fight it, impeachment supporters
take advantage of it: the worse is the situation,
the better, because government's popularity
decreases.
We should join forces in favour of the best
for the country's people.
Congress should foster solutions. Congress
is blocking them, instead. (We shall see more
details about it in future episodes.)
TOO GOOD TO BE TRUE
Dilma has not committed any crime. The impeachment
is being forged by many reasons, and has many
coordinated actions and actors.
As we saw, the reasons include:
- true action against corruption
- support for a political reform
- end of media oligopoly
- trillions of pre-salt petroleoum
- Homeland of Education plan
- BRICS bank
- huge infra-structure investments
As a consequence, this brings the opposition
of:
- real corrupts and criminals
- career politicians
- mainstream media
- overseas oil companies
- all which profits on ignorance
- NATO, IMF, World Bank
- imperialist powers
As we can see, the amount of goodness is proportional
to the amount of powers and forces that joined
and acted against Workers Party's government,
supporting the current fraud of Dilma's impeachment.
We are currently hostages of
a criminal interim government.
We just want our legitimate government back.
There is an ongoing assault to the country.
An attempt to usurp power,
attending to foreign and private interests.
This is what is going on in Brazil.
Thank you for listening.
You can support this work by participating
in the discussion.
Just visit discuss.whatisgoingoninbrazil.com
Thank you.