To explain what is going on in Brazil right
now is quite easy.
It is also easy to understand.
Our President, Dilma Vana Rousseff, was elected
in 2014 with 54,501,118 votes.
It is the fourth consecutive win for the Worker's
Party in the presidential election.
Previously, Luis Inácio da Silva, known as
Lula, also from the Worker's Party, lost the
presidential elections three consecutive times:
in 1989, 1994 and 1998.
Lula was elected in 2002, and re-elected in
2006. Dilma was then elected in 2010, and
recently re-elected.
At the same time, in 2014 people elected the
most conservative congressmen since the end
of Brazilian military dictatorship.
Many of these Congressmen, through their action
in Congress, reveal that they act according
to the will of those who paid their campaigns
and now pay for their decision making. In
other words: they do not represent the will
of the people who voted on them; they represent
who pay them most.
In this scenario, we are witnessing the enacting
of an impeachment. The law enforces a series
of conditions for it to happen.
The Brazilian Constitution requires a criminal
act from the President. But Dilma has not
committed any crime.
In fact, it is quite the opposite: she is
well-known as "rigid" and "inflexible", truly
meaning that she is not open to illicit negotiations.
Even among her political enemies, Dilma is
known as being honest.
As there is no illegal act, common
and ordinary administrative acts
were transformed into crimes.
Passionate, fraudulent discourses
are repeated exhaustively,
trying to assert that there is a crime.
While intensively pushed by the mainstream
media, these speeches do not stand a rational
and unbiased analysis, as they do not stand
to the facts.
There is no crime. At all.
There is no single act from the President
which can be pointed as evidence. Sincerely
speaking, there is no crime as there is no
intention of a crime.
This is why the process is being flagged as
a coup (a government overthrow): because the
Constitution requirements are not being respected.
What makes the situation outstanding is the
reason why these Congressmen are pushing this
injustice forward.
Let me tell you: they are doing this as a
way to interrupt the course of current investigations
against corruption, which Dilma's government
promotes and support.
Yes, you heard right: criminal politicians
joined forces to enforce an end, or at least
a severe limit to the ongoing operations led
by the Federal Police and other legal institutions.
This utter madness would not have the minimal
chance to happen without strong support of
an amazing power: the mainstream media.
In Brazil, almost the entirety of the media
business is owned by a handful of families.
It is said that six families control 80% of
all media and publication channels.
This is why you need a citizen - not a company
- to tell you what is going on.
The media channels´ massive and expensive
apparatus is such that their distorted narrative
has been pushed into a significant portion
of the population, who has been tricked into
thinking that their version is the only existing
one, corresponding to the facts.
In the next episodes many aspects and actors
of this drama shall be detailed, as well as
why and how the narrative of the mainstream
media is so disconnected from what is really
going on in Brazil.
Thank you for listening.
You can support this work by participating
in the discussion.
Please visit discuss.whatisgoingoninbrazil.com
and leave your feedback.
Thank you.